We call this meeting of the Board of
Adjustments for May 21st, 2026 to order.
Please call roll.
>> Dustin Brown.
>> Here.
>> Charity Campfield.
>> Curtis Clayball.
>> Here.
>> Michael O'Donnell.
>> Aaron LeBlanc.
>> Here.
>> Linda Burt.
>> Chair, you have a quorum.
>> Thank you.
All right, our first order of business
is the approval of minutes.
Um, the chair would entertain a motion.
And do we have a second?
>> I second.
>> Uh, any comments?
All right, all in favor say I. I.
>> I.
>> All opposed?
All right, with that the motion passes.
Um, and then with that we'll turn it
over for um, the first order of
business.
>> Item A, request PUDC-26-66,
conditional use request for outdoor
sales within the LI zone. Located at lot
two, block one, Overland Trails Business
Park.
Agent is Jennifer Elfram and case
planner is Morgan Dennis.
>> Thank you. Please, please go ahead.
>> Chair, members of the board, Morgan
Dennis, Planning and Development. This
is a conditional use request for outdoor
storage and sales at lot two, block one,
Overland Trails Business Park.
This parcel is located in the LI light
industrial zone district with
surrounding zones being LI and CB,
community business. The future land use
map designates this area as mixed use
employment. This designation promotes
the development of industrial and
commercial uses.
The proposed use is an expansion of the
use on the property to the south. The
property to the south is currently being
used for outdoor sales per the code.
The applicant initially asked for
outdoor storage, but with this being an
expansion of an existing site site,
staff added outdoor sales to the
approved motion to reduce the
possibility of the applicant needing to
return before the board for changes
during the site plan process.
The site is currently vacant, but there
is a site plan submitted with this
conditional use. This site will likely
have to go through the site plan process
and meet the standards for the light
industrial zone district. The operating
characteristics will be complementary to
the surrounding area. Business hour
hours and number of trips are expected
to be no different than those of the
existing business. There are no expected
visible or audible impacts to the
property.
The intent of the LI zone is for uses
that cannot readily be fit into other
general business or mixed-use areas due
to nature or intensity of operations.
Outdoor storage and sales is within the
intent of the LI zone as it is a
component of this business that is not
compatible with other commercially zoned
areas. With this, staff recommends
approval and I stand for questions.
>> Thank you. Any questions for staff?
Thank you.
Is there anyone from the applicant that
would like to speak tonight?
Thank you.
All right, any other public testimony?
All right, with that we'll close public
comment and the
any
any comment from anyone on the board?
All right, the chair will take maintain
a motion.
>> Mr. Chairman.
I move to approve a conditional use
request for the use of outdoor sales and
outdoor storage at lot two block one
Overland Trails Business Park as
presented by the applicant as the
application meets all review criteria
outlined in UDC section 2.2.4.D
as in dog.
>> Thank you. Do we have a second?
>> I'll second.
>> Any further comment?
All right. Staff, please call roll.
>> Curtis Claybaugh.
>> Yes.
>> Charity Campfield.
>> Dustin Brown.
>> Yes.
>> Michael O'Donnell.
>> Hi.
>> Aaron LeBlanc.
>> Yes.
>> Linda Burt.
>> Chair, the motion passes.
>> Thank you. Let's go to the next item.
>> Item B, request PUDC-26-279.
Variance request to allow a 6-ft
building setback from the north property
line adjacent to a street within the LI
zone located at 2420 East 7th Street.
The agent is Tim Gentleman and the case
planner is Morgan Dennis.
>> All right. Please go ahead.
>> Uh Mr. Chair, members of the board, this
is a variance request to reduce the
setback in the LI zone district.
Um the request is to reduce the setback
from 25 ft to 6 ft along the Nationway
frontage. This site has historically
been used for commercial and storage
pur- purposes. This site is currently
vacant as the previous structure
underwent demolition due to structural
failure brought on by natural disaster.
The UDC does allow for non-conforming
buildings destroyed by natural disasters
to be rebuilt, but reconstruction must
start within a 12-month period. This
property was not reconstructed within
that time period.
This lot contains unique dimensions that
create narrow portions of the lot that
widen as the lot heads east.
Due to the previous
locate the previous structure location,
there is existing water and sewer
utilities located at the narrow
portions of the parcel. Strict
application of the LI setback could be
applied and met on the property if the
building was moved to the rear portion
of the property, but this is not without
significant burden to the applicant due
to the existing utilities needing to be
moved.
The adjustment for 6-ft setback on
Nationway is the minimum adjustment on
the property. Um staff recommends
approval and I stand for questions.
>> Thank you. Any questions for staff?
All right. Is there anyone representing
the applicant here that would like to
speak on this item?
All right.
Anyone online by chance?
>> Mr. Tim Gentleman is online.
>> Yes.
Can you hear me?
>> Yes, we can hear you.
>> Okay.
>> Can I swear you in? Would you like to
provide public comment?
>> Sure, I would. Um I would just like to
add that um
>> Well, um hang on just 1 second. Let me
swear you in real quick. Um
Can you state your name and your
address, please?
>> Uh my name is Tim Gentleman. I reside at
1005 Murray Hill Drive, Cheyenne,
Wyoming. Representing
>> Do you swear to tell the truth and only
the truth in the matter before the Board
of Adjustments?
>> I do.
>> All right, please proceed.
>> Yeah, I would just like to highlight
that we did have a building failure back
in March of '21. We had a significant
snowfall that year, which we had a
partial collapse of the roof.
Um at that time we determined that it
was an older building, metal siding, but
it was a wood structure. We decided to
go to a metal building with red iron
structure.
Um
Like I said, um this was also during
COVID, so we were unable to at that time
meet the 12-month period to re-permit.
Uh so that's what's brought us in front
of the board today.
>> Thank you.
Does anyone have any uh questions for
the applicant?
All right. Is there anyone else online
that may want to testify?
All right. With that, we'll close public
comment, and the chair will entertain a
motion.
>> I move to approve a setback variance
request for 2420 East 7th Street,
reducing setback requirements from 25 ft
to 6 ft from the Nation Way frontage to
allow a building to be constructed with
access to existing water and sewer
lines, noting that the application meets
all the review criteria.
>> Thank you. Do we have a second?
>> I second. I second. Um
>> All right. With that, let's call roll.
>> Chair, this Clayball.
>> Yes.
>> Charity Campfield.
>> Dustin Brown.
>> Yes.
>> Michael O'Donnell.
>> Aye.
>> Aaron LeBlanc.
>> Yes.
>> Linda Burke.
>> Chair, the motion passes.
>> Thank you. On to other business.
>> Um Chair, the only other business I have
is that uh we will have a board meeting
next month on June 18th.
>> Okay. Thank you. With that, we'll we
will Oh, yeah. Go ahead, sir.
>> And chair, members of the board, Charles
Bloom, Planning and Development
Director. The only thing I have to add
is this Saturday at the library between
10:00 and 1:00, there is a
I believe it's a bicycle safety rodeo
type of event that's going on. There
will also be
um booths regarding our Safe streets for
all plan. Um that is a federal plan,
federally funded plan that the MPO is um
working through. So, that'll be from
10:00 to 1:00. Um all people are
invited, anyone with children and kids.
There's like uh like a children's
bicycle course, stuff like that that'll
be there.
Um in addition, if you have a bicycle,
there'll be a slow roll that's hosted uh
by the Cheyenne Slow Roll group. That's
at noon. Um that will depart the
library. Nice, easy, casual
bike ride for anybody that can
participate. No charge for any of that.
So, hope to see some of you there on
Saturday.
Thank you.
All right. Oh, and chair, that was our
first variance we've had in over 18
months. That's a new record, so I'm kind
of bummed that we have to start over.
This count is very frustrating.
>> Yeah, and that was a pretty It was long
ago. It was long ago.
>> Like those streets don't get broken very
often.
>> All right, with that, we are adjourned.